<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>com.modrinth.ModrinthApp</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <name>Modrinth App</name>
  <summary>Modrinth's game launcher</summary>
  <description>
    <p>A unique, open source Minecraft launcher that allows you to play your favorite mods, and keep them up to date, all in one neat little package</p>
  </description>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#81f3af</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#033018</color>
  </branding>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
    <category>ActionGame</category>
    <category>AdventureGame</category>
    <category>Simulation</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>game</keyword>
    <keyword>minecraft</keyword>
    <keyword>mc</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <url type="homepage">https://modrinth.com</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/modrinth/code/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/modrinth/code</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/modrinth/code</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.modrinth.ModrinthApp.desktop</launchable>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.10.27" date="2026-01-23">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed installing content from Discover refusing to create NeoForge instances.</li>
          <li>Added circuit-breaker logic to prevent Modrinth App from spamming API requests during downtime.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.26" date="2026-01-15">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed many checkboxes not having labels for screen readers.</li>
          <li>Fixed 'Jump back in' setting not working sometimes.</li>
          <li>Fixed crash issues when opening folders.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Many other changes since the previous flatpak-supported version 0.10.15. See our GitHub releases page for more info.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.15" date="2025-10-27">
      <description/>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.12" date="2025-10-15">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed cache sticking around for way too long (30 hours instead of 30 minutes).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.11" date="2025-10-15">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed ads being able to play audio.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.10" date="2025-10-04">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed Minecraft versions 1.12.2 and earlier failing to install.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.9" date="2025-10-04">
      <description>
        <p>Security fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a couple Modrinth Pack (<code>.mrpack</code>) importing security vulnerabilities.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.8" date="2025-09-29">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Overhauled Modrinth App updater to make it easier to stay up-to-date.</li>
          <li>Updates will now be downloaded in the background to make a seamless updating experience.</li>
          <li>When an update is downloaded, it will prompt you to reload the app.</li>
          <li>If a metered internet connection is detected, it will ask you before downloading the update.</li>
          <li>Fixed how transparency is handled on the skins page. (Contributed by Jerozgen)</li>
          <li>Removed the 'Advanced' toggle in the Instance creation interface.</li>
          <li>Improved version selection when installing content.</li>
          <li>Installing versions from the Discover content page will now install a version according to your filters, rather than simply the latest.</li>
          <li>Dependencies will now download with the same logic as the content being installed.</li>
          <li>Non-mod projects and dependencies will now be installed properly.</li>
          <li>Fixed window dragging issues with the top bar. (Contributed by aervxa)</li>
          <li>Fixed an empty servers.dat file being created when one doesn't already exist, preventing certain mods from providing defaults.</li>
          <li>Fixed long creator names overflowing on project pages.</li>
          <li>Strings in Markdown descriptions that look like domain names or IP addresses will no longer automatically be converted to links, such as `README.md`.</li>
          <li>When adding friends, unknown users will now show an error.</li>
          <li>Pressing 'Enter' after typing in a friend's username will now send the friend request.</li>
          <li>Improved error handling from Modrinth API.</li>
          <li>Fixed the white flash when the app is opened on certain systems. (Contributed by aervxa)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.7" date="2025-08-20">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed Quick Play not working with Singleplayer worlds.</li>
          <li>Updated ad fallback to Medal promo.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.6" date="2025-08-15">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed Forge versions between 1.17.1 and 1.20.3 failing to launch.</li>
          <li>Fixed search page constantly resetting back to page 1.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.5" date="2025-08-15">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>On Windows, the app will now install per-user rather than system-wide.</li>
          <li>This allows future versions of Modrinth App to update seamlessly if the user is not an administrator.</li>
          <li>When updating to this version, the app will prompt you for Admin elevation in order to remove the old system-wide installation.</li>
          <li>Desktop shortcuts should be migrated automatically to the new installation location.</li>
          <li>Improvements to the Skins page.</li>
          <li>Fixed skins being mirrored.</li>
          <li>Added automatic detection of arm style from skin file.</li>
          <li>Improved performance of skin renderer.</li>
          <li>Added anti-aliasing to the skin renderer to make it appear smoother.</li>
          <li>Tweaked the rendering of the spotlight below the player model.</li>
          <li>Allow offline servers to still be joined from Worlds tab. Some servers display as offline as a privacy measure, or only start up once a player attempts to join.</li>
          <li>Improved Modrinth user account login to use your default web browser.</li>
          <li>Updated the appearance and functionality of error notifications to match the Modrinth website.</li>
          <li>Fixed search not returning to first page when filters are changed.</li>
          <li>Fixed modpacks showing up with the "Optimization" tag on Home page even when it's not a featured category on the project.</li>
          <li>Improved pinging Minecraft servers for older versions in the Worlds tab to more closely match how the client would ping them.</li>
          <li>Added Quick Play functionality for Minecraft servers on versions before 1.20.</li>
          <li>Fixed the tracking of last played time for Minecraft servers on versions before 1.7.2.</li>
          <li>Fixed the order when sorting Library page by game version.</li>
          <li>Fixed the incompatibility warning not remembering the version you clicked on.</li>
          <li>Added common snapping points to memory allocation sliders.</li>
          <li>Increased the size of the 'Logs' page on instances.</li>
          <li>Fixed failure when clicking 'Test' on Java versions.</li>
          <li>Fixed the back/forward buttons appearing with white icons in light mode.</li>
          <li>Fixed 'Party Alex' skin not using slim character model.</li>
          <li>Improved resilience of Minecraft launching on Java 8 under certain circumstances.</li>
          <li>Added system for showing users surveys to provide feedback on their experience with Modrinth App.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>**This update was originally launched as 0.10.4, but was pulled due to issues with many functions of the app.**</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.3" date="2025-07-07">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a workaround for Java 8 instances failing to load.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Known issues</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Java installations will show as 'Failed' when you test them. This is a visual bug, and does not mean the Java installation is not working.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.2" date="2025-07-06">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added additional default skins from free official Minecraft skin packs.</li>
          <li>Fixed some parts of the player model on Skins page rendering incorrectly.</li>
          <li>Fixed a number of issues with skin images not loading on macOS.</li>
          <li>Fixed old Forge versions not loading properly.</li>
          <li>Fixed a typo in Appearance settings for hiding Skins page nametag.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Known issues</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Java installations will show as 'Failed' when you test them. This is a visual bug, and does not mean the Java installation is not working.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.1" date="2025-07-05">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>News section will now only show up to 4 articles.</li>
          <li>Fixed critical issue with updating on Windows.</li>
          <li>Fixed search being broken after a query that yields no results.</li>
          <li>Fixed 'Jump back in' section on Home page not working.</li>
          <li>Fixed too many Quick Instance items on the sidebar causing the UI to overflow.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.0" date="2025-07-04">
      <description>
        <p>Added</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added Skins page as a beta feature. There may be some minor bugs with it, but we'd love to get user feedback on this feature as it's been one of our most highly requested features.</li>
          <li>Save as many of your own skins as you'd like to swap between them at any moment.</li>
          <li>Pick a default cape, or override the cape on any of your saved skin profiles to tailor each look perfectly.</li>
          <li>Choose between any of the default Minecraft skins.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated News section to pull data from our new custom news feed.</li>
          <li>Fixed videos from GitHub not working in project descriptions.</li>
          <li>Fixed data related to a world not being deleted from the database when the world was deleted.</li>
          <li>Standardized relative date timestamps across the app.</li>
          <li>Fixed 'Reset icon' button for Singleplayer worlds state not being reset when opening the Edit interface.</li>
          <li>Fixed 'Repair' button showing while an instance is installing.</li>
          <li>Fixed instances with non-UTF8 text files failing to launch or import.</li>
          <li>Fixed launch hooks being unable to be cleared on an instance.</li>
          <li>Fixed search results breaking if page number goes out of bounds.</li>
          <li>Fixed servers running old Minecraft versions not showing last played time.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.5" date="2025-05-01">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed certain mods with a large number of versions not being able to be installed or load their versions.</li>
          <li>Fixed server descriptions not being rendered with the Minecraft font.</li>
          <li>When installing a modpack, the page will now change to the instance once it's created.</li>
          <li>Last played time for existing servers will now be loaded from log files instead of displaying "Never played".</li>
          <li>Home page's "Jump back in" section will now display in multiple columns when the screen is very large.</li>
          <li>Added the ability to launch the instance from a World entry on the Home page.</li>
          <li>Added the ability to hide a world from the Home page.</li>
          <li>Added an appearance setting to only show instances instead of worlds on the Home page.</li>
          <li>Fixed Home page rendering being blocked by server pings.</li>
          <li>Fixed Home page sometimes not sending the correct protocol version when fetching server data.</li>
          <li>Fixed server data not being loaded immediately after adding it.</li>
          <li>Fixed Worlds tab filters showing up in the wrong situations.</li>
          <li>Fixed new Singleplayer worlds not being added to the Worlds tab without a refresh.</li>
          <li>Fixed an excessive number of items showing up in "Jump back in" sometimes.</li>
          <li>Fixed critical error modal cutting off long single-line error messages.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.4" date="2025-04-27">
      <description>
        <p>Added</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a Worlds tab to instances that allow you to manage your worlds and servers directly from the app</li>
          <li>Server ping, play count, and descriptions will all show before having to open the game.</li>
          <li>Add, edit, and remove servers</li>
          <li>Edit and delete singleplayer worlds</li>
          <li>Added 'Quick Play' functionality, allowing you to jump straight into worlds and servers from the app</li>
          <li>Added new launcher-log.txt file to log stdout to a file, similar to the Minecraft Launcher which can be helpful for debugging.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Overhauled the 'Jump back in' section of the Home page, showing recently played worlds instead of just instances. This supports the new 'Quick Play' functionality, allowing you to jump back into your recent worlds (on supported Minecraft versions 1.20+)</li>
          <li>Improved the fatal error dialog to show debug information more prominently, and allow you to copy it to share with support.</li>
          <li>Fixed the display of critical announcements that has been broken since 0.9.0.</li>
          <li>Fixed content authors not displaying properly on Content page if the content was owned by an organization.</li>
          <li>Fixed random errors on the Library page, causing no instances to load.</li>
          <li>Fixed .mrpack file association on Linux.</li>
          <li>Fixed occasional failures when moving app directory between disks.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.3" date="2025-02-06">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Prevent ads from being able to open additional windows.</li>
          <li>Fixed update checking only checking for mod updates.</li>
          <li>Fixed issue importing newer Prism instances.</li>
          <li>Fixed issue where instances get stuck "Installing" forever when the app is closed during an install.</li>
          <li>Minecraft profile is now updated every time the user's token is refreshed.</li>
          <li>Improved ability for package managers to update Modrinth App by skipping the updater at runtime with an environment variable.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.2" date="2024-12-25">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Prevent ads from being able to play audio.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.1" date="2024-12-24">
      <description>
        <p>Added</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added filter to filter projects by disabled.</li>
          <li>Re-added back/forward navigation buttons.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed environment tags missing from search.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where ads could play audio.</li>
          <li>Changed content enable/disable buttons to toggle switches.</li>
          <li>Show "install" button at all time on project cards.</li>
          <li>Fixed issue where cards would shrink when clicking button inside them causing click not to register.</li>
          <li>Made sidebar hide instantly.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2024-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New, updated design that brings the app in-line with the website.</li>
          <li>A dynamic sidebar that adjusts to the most relevant content for each page, and keeps the ad in a consistent place instead of moving all around your screen.</li>
          <li>More organized settings interfaces that makes each option clearer and easier to find.</li>
          <li>Managing your content is much easier with enhanced filters for content types or checking for updates.</li>
          <li>Content discovery has been overhauled and now has fully-featured project pages that match the website.</li>
          <li>Instances now show your total play time, and will show the last time you played on the Home screen.</li>
          <li>The library page now gives responsive feedback as instances are installing.</li>
          <li>The beginnings of a Friends system. In the future, you will be able to share the instances you’re playing and invite them to servers.</li>
          <li>Access your most recent instances with ease with Quick Instances.</li>
          <li>Fixed “Database is locked” errors on devices with slow disks.</li>
          <li>Fixed a few edge cases where API downtime could lead to an invalid state.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.9" date="2024-10-16">
      <description>
        <p>A new version of the Modrinth App has been released!</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.8" date="2024-10-04" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>A small patch update to fix some bugs and common issues in the Modrinth App</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Adds an option to disable personalized ads</li>
          <li>Prevent audio from playing in ads</li>
          <li>Fixes install mod to profile modal being broken</li>
          <li>Fix Modrinth Plus link in advertisement opening multiple times</li>
          <li>Update Modrinth Plus advertisement to be more accurate</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.7" date="2024-09-10" type="stable">
      <description><p>Small hotfix update fixing a regression causing profile icons not to be able to be set!</p></description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.6" date="2024-09-10" type="stable">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix crashing on Intel-based Macs for all versions of Minecraft</li>
          <li>Allow arrow key navigation for gallery images, and ESC to close out of it</li>
          <li>Fixed occurrences where users would not be able to use app with "Database is locked" error</li>
          <li>Fix ads appearing above content (gallery images, settings page)</li>
          <li>Fix performance / excess memory usage caused by ads</li>
          <li>Fix Modrinth+ link opening multiple times</li>
          <li>Fixes multiple app installs of the Modrinth App</li>
          <li>Updates executable name on Windows back to "Modrinth App.exe"</li>
          <li>FIx not being able to overwrite java arguments or custom env vars with an empty field</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.5" date="2024-08-30" type="stable">
      <description/>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.2" date="2024-08-22" type="stable">
      <url>https://blog.modrinth.com/p/introducing-modrinth-refreshed-site-look-new-advertising-system</url>
      <description>
        <p>Over the last few months, we’ve been overhauling the internals of the Modrinth App to drastically improve performance and stability. Over one hundred issues have been closed with this update alone! Here’s a short list of the major changes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Newer versions of Forge and NeoForge now work!</li>
          <li>Migrated internal launcher data to use SQLite. The app now loads in less than 40ms on average (compared to ~2.5s before)!</li>
          <li>Fixed issues where profiles could disappear in the UI</li>
          <li>Fixed random cases of the UI freezing up during actions</li>
          <li>Fixed directory changes being very inconsistent</li>
          <li>Drastically improved offline mode</li>
          <li>Fix freezing and include crash reports logs tab</li>
          <li>And over one hundred more fixes!</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.1" date="2024-04-24" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/modrinth/code/releases/tag/v0.7.1</url>
      <description>
        <p>Modrinth App v0.7.1 added support for Minecraft 1.20.5 and fixed a ton of bugs and issues.</p>
        <p>Main improvements ⭐</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Minecraft authentication has been rewritten to match the official Minecraft Launcher, providing a much smoother login experience with fewer issues.</li>
          <li>Added support for Java 21 and Minecraft 1.20.5.</li>
          <li>Java installations are handled for you automatically by default for a more seamless experience, but can be manually configured in Settings.</li>
          <li>Introduced better error handling to assist you with fixing problems, such as Minecraft authentication issues.</li>
          <li>Modpacks with client-side only overrides will now be installed properly.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bugfixes 🐛</p>
        <ul>
          <li>No longer enables LWJGL debugging mode by default, potentially improving game performance.</li>
          <li>Changing app directory to a different drive now properly moves all your files.</li>
          <li>Live log will no longer glitch out and will not use as much memory.</li>
          <li>Removed java_options flag that caused random fatal Java errors.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>What's next for Modrinth App? 👀</p>
        <p>We're working on these, but they didn't quite make it into this release just yet! Keep an eye out for v0.8 in the coming weeks!</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add support for recent versions of Minecraft Forge 🔨: Recent versions of the Forge installer have broken how we install Forge. We're working on implementing ForgeWrapper to more easily support Forge like other launchers do.</li>
          <li>Improve logging for debug purposes 📜: Other launchers append extra data or create extra log files to provide more debugging information, and many users have provided feedback that Modrinth App not providing these makes it harder to provide support for Modrinth App users. We're working to improve our logging to be just as easy as other launchers.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2024-04-23" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/modrinth/code/releases/tag/v0.7.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>What's Changed</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Remove lwjgl debugging argument. by @qtchaos in #959</li>
          <li>Switch from stdout log to latest log MOD-595 by @darling in #964</li>
          <li>Config transfer by @thesuzerain in #951</li>
          <li>adds credentials refresh save by @thesuzerain in #1030</li>
          <li>Use Tokio directly instead of Tauri in io.rs by @KnifesmithCode in #1087</li>
          <li>chore: update dependencies by @ToBinio in #1103</li>
          <li>Fix client-overrides not getting extracted by @MelanX in #1120</li>
          <li>Switch to official launcher auth by @Geometrically in #1118</li>
          <li>Fix java installs by @Geometrically in #1123</li>
          <li>Bump to 0.7.0 + Add sign-in error by @Geometrically in #1133</li>
          <li>fix: version page by @ToBinio in #1121</li>
        </ul>
        <p>New Contributors</p>
        <ul>
          <li>@KnifesmithCode made their first contribution in #1087</li>
          <li>@MelanX made their first contribution in #1120</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.3" date="2023-12-14" type="stable">
      <url>https://github.com/modrinth/code/releases/tag/v0.6.3</url>
      <description>
        <p>What's changed</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Enable light mode and OLED mode as options by @triphora in #936</li>
          <li>Fix #901 - add YT nocookie and Discord to CSP by @triphora in #904</li>
          <li>Add text wrapping to project version names. by @qtchaos in #928</li>
          <li>Fix auth (finally) by @Geometrically in #937</li>
          <li>fix custom profile import for CF by @maxomatic458 in #914</li>
        </ul>
        <p>New Contributors</p>
        <ul>
          <li>@maxomatic458 made their first contribution in #914</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <provides>
    <binary>modrinth-app</binary>
    <mediatype>application/x-modrinth-modpack+zip</mediatype>
    <mediatype>x-scheme-handler/modrinth</mediatype>
  </provides>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <developer id="com.modrinth">
    <name>Rinth, Inc</name>
  </developer>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The home screen of the app</caption>
      <image>https://cdn-raw.modrinth.com/app-landing/app-screenshot.webp</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>An instance of Cobblemon in the app</caption>
      <image>https://cdn-raw.modrinth.com/app-landing/cobblemon-launcher.webp</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
